Finding Aid for the Perry H. Biddle, JR. Collection
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
Perry H. Biddle, Jr. Collection
1960-2002
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
MSS.0581
.84 linear_feet
Biography
Reverend Doctor Perry H. Biddle, Jr. received a B.A. from Davidson College in 1954; a M.Div. and Th.M. from Union Theological Seminary in 1958 and 1960, respectively; a Certificate in Theology from the New College of the University of Edinburgh in 1959; and a D.Mn. from Vanderbilt University in 1973. His pastoral work has taken him across the country and around the world as guest lecturer and preacher. His pastorates have included St. Andrews Presbyterian Church in Memphis, Tennessee; Westminster Presbyterian Church in Mobile, Alabama; First Presbyterian Church in Starksville, Mississippi; and Old Hickory Presbyterian Church in Old Hickory, Tennessee. He is a prolific writer, producing eighteen books for the clergy and laity as well as over a hundred articles for professional journals and magazines.
Rev. Dr. Biddle, Jr. retired from active ministry in 1997.
Scope and Content
The Perry H. Biddle, Jr. Collection contains eighteen book and pamphlet publications as well as a copy of a dissertation submitted to Union Theological Seminary in support of his Th.M. degree in 1960. Publication dates for the material range from 1960 to 2002. Topics covered by the publications include funeral management and counseling, health and healing, marriage ceremony management and counseling, hospital visitation manuals, preaching guides and lectionaries, and suicide counseling.
- Publications
  - Funeral Manuals
    - Abingdon Funeral Manual. Nashville, Tennessee: Abingdon Press, 1976 (Box 1)
    - Abingdon Funeral Manual, Revised. Nashville, Tennessee: Abingdon Press, 1990 (Box 1)
    - A Funeral Manual. Revised edition. Grand Rapids, Michigan: William B. Eerdmans Publishing Company, 1994 (Box 1)
  - Health and Healing
    - Humor and Healing. Second edition. Palm Beach, Florida: Desert Ministries, Inc., 1996 (Box 1)
  - Hospital Manuals
    - Abingdon Hospital Visitation Manual. Nashville, Tennessee: Abingdon Press, 1988 (Box 1)
    - A Hospital Visitation Manual. Grand Rapids, Michigan: William B. Eerdmans Publishing Company, 1994 (Box 1)
  - Marriage Manuals
    - Abingdon Marriage Manual. Nashville, Tennessee: Abingdon Press, 1974 (Box 1)
    - The Goodness of Marriage: A Devotional Book for Newlyweds. Nashville, Tennessee: The Upper Room, 1984 (Box 1)
    - Marrying Again: A Guide for Christians. Nashville, Tennessee: Abingdon Press, 1986 (Box 1)
    - Abingdon Marriage Manual. Revised edition. Nashville, Tennessee: Abingdon Press, 1987 (Box 1)
    - A Marriage Manual. Revised edition. Grand Rapids, Michigan: William B. Eerdmans Publishing Company, 1994 (Box 1)
    - The Goodness of Marriage: A Devotional Book for Newlyweds. Revised edition. Macon, Georgia: Smyth and Helwys Publishing, Inc., 2002 (Box 1)
  - Preaching Manuals
    - “The Preaching of Heaven and Hell”, (M.T. diss., Union Theological Seminary, 1960) (Box 1)
- Publications
  - Preaching Manuals
    - Lectionary Preaching Workbook, Series II, Cycle B, for Use with Common, Lutheran, and Roman Catholic Lectionaries. Lima, Ohio: C.S.S. Publishing Co., Inc., 1987 (Box 2)
    - Lectionary Preaching Workbook, Series II, Cycle C, for Use with Common, Lutheran, and Roman Catholic Lectionaries. Lima, Ohio: C.S.S. Publishing Co., Inc., 1988 (Box 2)
    - Preaching the Lectionary: A Workbook for Year A. Louisville, Kentucky: Westminster/John Knox Press, 1989 (Box 2)
    - Preaching the Lectionary: A Workbook for Year B. Louisville, Kentucky: Westminster/John Knox Press, 1990 (Box 2)
    - Preaching the Lectionary: A Workbook for Year B. Louisville, Kentucky: Westminster/John Knox Press, 1991 (Box 2)
  - Suicide
    - Reflections on Suicide. Second edition. Palm Beach, Florida: Desert Ministries, Inc., 1996 (Box 2)